Guide to the Small Manuscript Collections
The Wittliff Collections
- J. Edwin Smith booklets, 1958; Smith, J. Edwin
  - Two copies of a booklet titled " Some Notes on Justice for the People of Texas from J. Edwin Smith candidate for Associate Justice of the Supreme Court of Texas Subject to the Democratic Primary July 26, 1958." (Folder SMC 0056)
- Marcia Ball postcards, 1998-1999; Ball, Marcia
  Women musicians -- Texas
  - Tour date post cards for "Marcia Ball Band", one with a note signed by Ball, 1998-1999 (Folder SMC 0057)
- Texas Hatters brochure, circa 1989; Texas Hatters
  Cowboys -- Clothing
  - Brochure for Texas Hatters. Manny Gammage of Texas Hatters made hats for the Lonesome Dove miniseries, circa 1989 (Folder SMC 0058)
- Charles Blankenship collection on The Dead Presidents' Club, 1995-1997; Blankenship, Charles
  Dramatists -- Texas; Blankenship, Charles; King, Larry L.
  - The Dead Presidents' Club playbill signed by Larry L. King (Folder SMC 0059)
  - Flyer advertising a performance of The Dead Presidents' Club at Southwest Texas State University (Folder SMC 0059)
  - Clippings (5) (Folder SMC 0059)
  - Bound copy of The Dead Presidents' Club script with a name plate of Charles Blankenship and signed by King and four actors in the play (Folder SMC 0059)
  - Bound copy of The Dead Presidents' Club script with "rewrites as of September, 1996" (Folder SMC 0059)
- Billy Lee Brammer letters, circa 1962; Brammer, Billy Lee
  Authors, American -- Texas; King, Larry L.
  - Two letters from Billy Lee Brammer to his agent, Marie Wilson, January 19, 1962, undated (Folder SMC 0060)
  - Letter from Billy Lee Brammer to Larry L. King, undated (Folder SMC 0060)
- Antonio Turok galley proofs, 1998; Turok, Antonio, 1955-
  Photographers -- Mexico
  - Galley proofs for Chiapas: El Fin del Silencio (Chiapas: The End of Silence), 1998 (Folder SMC 0061)
- Tad Hershorn collection on Eddie Durham, 1938-1993
  Jazz musicians -- Texas; African American musicians; Durham, Eddie, 1906-1987
  - Two papers about Durham (Folder SMC 0062)
  - Program from Durham's 80th birthday celebration, circa 1986 (Folder SMC 0062)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1938-1993 (Folder SMC 0062)
  - A letter from Eddie Durham's son about to the New Jersey Jazz Society (Folder SMC 0062)
- Michael Hall's Lubbock interview transcripts, circa 2001; Hall, Michael
  Transcripts of interviews with multiple individuals about the Lubbock, Texas music history. Interviewees/subjects include Lloyd Maines, Jo Carol Pierce, Waylon Jennings, Angela Strehli, Delbert McClinton, Terry Allen, Joe Ely, Jimmy Dale Gilmore, and Butch Hancock among others.
  Musicians -- Interviews; Lubbock (Tex.)
  - Copies of transcripts of interviews between Michael Hall of Texas Monthly. Some transcripts are in email format and there are two transcripts where the interviewee is not clearly identified., circa July 2001 (Folder SMC 0063)
- Texas Press Association collection on Laura Furman, 2001; Texas Press Association
  Women authors, Texan; Furman, Laura
  - Biographical information and promotional material about author Laura Furman, 2001 (Folder SMC 0064)
- Decherd Turner letters, 1955-1957
  Dobie, J. Frank (James Frank), 1888-1964; Kirkland, Elithe Hamilton; Bedichek, Roy
  - Letters to Decherd Turner from Lewis Nordyke, J. Frank Dobie, A. C. Greene, Elithe Hamilton, Loula Grace Erdman, Roy Bedichek, and William E. Barrett, 1955-1957 (Folder SMC 0065)
- Josephine Etlinger promotional material, circa 1987; Etlinger, Josephine Blume Seeliger
  Women authors, Texan
  - Promotional material for Sweetest You Can Find by Josephine Etlinger, circa 1987 (Folder SMC 0066)
- Tex Ritter sheet music, 1945; Ritter, Tex
  Cowboys -- Songs and music
  - Sheet music for "Christmas Carols by the Old Corral" by Johnny Lange and Archie Gottler. Recorded by Tex Ritter, published by Texas Ritter Music Publications, 1945 (Folder SMC 0067)
- J. Frank Dobie draft, 1952; Dobie, J. Frank (James Frank), 1888-1964
  - Photocopy of typescript of "The Hawk That Missed His Aim" by J. Frank Dobie with handwritten notes, November 16, 1952 (Folder SMC 0068)
- Eddie Durham article, 2002
  African American musicians; Durham, Eddie, 1906-1987
  - "Eddie Durham: Jazz man had his roots in San Marcos" by Carol Coughlin. Appeared in the San Marcos Record, June 6, 2002 (Folder SMC 0069)
- Farm Aid informational packet, 2001; Farm Aid (Fund raising enterprise)
  Concerts
  - Farm Aid informational packet which contains a folder, brochure, program, newsletter, letter about Farm Aid, 2001 (Folder SMC 0070)
- Connie Todd collection on The Red Headed Stranger, circa 1985; Todd, Connie
  Materials relating to the production of The Red Headed Stranger. Connie Todd was casting director and director's assistant. Wittliff was the screenwriter, director, and co-exuctive producer.
  Motion pictures -- Production and direction; William D. Wittliff; Nelson, Willie, 1933-
  - Rosters, daily reports, shooting schedules, call sheets, phone messages, production crew lists, handwritten "to do" lists, circa 1985 (Folder SMC 0071)
- Austin-Bergstrom International Airport music schedules, July-August 2002; Coplin, Nancy
  Music -- Texas -- Austin; Austin-Bergstrom International Airport (Tex.)
  - Performance schedules for the Hill Country Bar and Highland Lakes Bar at the Austin-Bergstrom International Airport, July-August 2002 (Folder SMC 0072)
- John Graves book covers, undated
  - Seventeen book covers for Goodbye to a River by John Graves (Folder SMC 0073)
- Walter Prescott and Terrell Webb photographs, 1962-1976
  Webb, Walter Prescott; Webb, Terrell
  - Eight black and white photographs. One of Walter Prescott Webb, three of Terrell Webb, and four of them together, 1962-1976 (Folder SMC 0074)
- Betty Hannstein Adams typescript, undated; Adams, Betty Hannstein
  - Typescript of "An Unexpected Dividend" (The correspondence between Walter Prescott Webb and Terrell Maverick Webb), edited by Betty Hannstein Adams, with corrections, undated (Folder SMC 0075)
- Selena fan photograph, undated
  Women musicians -- Texas; Selena, 1971-1995
  - Photograph of a fan holding an image of Tejano singer, Selena [8" x 10"] black/white, undated (Folder SMC 0076)
- Dick Heaberlin academic paper for John Graves Symposium, 2002; Heaberlin, Dick
  - Typescript of "Of Dachshunds and Dashes: Subjects and Style in E. B. White and John Graves," written for the "Presentation of Academic Papers" for the John Graves symposium, September 6, 2002 (Folder SMC 0077)
- Katherine Anne Porter Preservation Project plans, 1998
  Historic buildings -- Conservation and restoration
  - Letter and planning documents related to the renovation of the Katherine Anne Porter House in Kyle, TX, December 4, 1998 (Folder SMC 0078)
- James Langston academic paper for John Graves Symposium, 2002; Langston, James
  - Typescript of "'Pie en la Patria': Speaking landscape and new pastoral in "Goodbye to a River", written for the "Presentation of Academic Papers" for the John Graves symposium, September 6, 2002 (Folder SMC 0079)
- Suzanne Winckler collection on "Women of Texas Monthly", 1982; Winckler, Suzanne, 1946-
  Materials from "Women of Texas Monthly", a project developed by Suzanne Winckler.
  Texas Monthly, Inc.
  - Narrative by Suzanne Winckler about the project, 1982 (Folder SMC 0080)
  - Photocopies of the "Women of Texas Monthly" group photographs, 1982 (Folder SMC 0080)
  - Tears sheet from an issue of Texas Monthly with the women's names highlighted, 1982 (Folder SMC 0080)
  - Notes, invoices, correspondence, 1982 (Folder SMC 0080)
  - Photographs with descriptions. Includes one 8" x 10" color photograph of the entire group., 1982 (Folder SMC 0080)
- Suzanne Winckler letters, 1977-2002; Winckler, Suzanne, 1946-
  Winckler, Suzanne, 1946-; Graves, John, 1920-2013; Harrigan, Stephen, 1948-; Broyles, William, Jr., 1944-; Faulk, John Henry; McPhee, John (John Angus), 1931-
  - Letters to Suzanne Winckler from John and Jane Graves, Steve Harrigan, Robert Frank, William Broyles, Jr. and John Henry Faulk (Folder SMC 0081)
  - Correspondence between Suzanne Winckler and John McPhee (Folder SMC 0081)
  - Letter to the Editorial and Art Department of Texas Monthly from Dominique Browning and letter about Browning from "GrCu" to the staff (Folder SMC 0081)
  - Photocopy of a letter addressed to "Dick," with a handwritten note in the margins to Suzanne Winckler from Rosemary. (Folder SMC 0081)
- Suzanne Winckler collection of Joe Greene, 1947, 1984; Winckler, Suzanne, 1946-
  Composers--Texas; Winckler, Suzanne, 1946-; Greene, Joe, 1915-1986
  - Copy of article Suzanne Winckler wrote about Joe Greene in January 1984 issue of Texas Monthy titled "Remember the Alamo--and Duz and Lux" Sheet music for "Across the Alley from the Alamo" by Greene (Folder SMC 0082)
  - Sheet music for "Across the Alley from the Alamo" by Joe Greene, 1947 (Folder SMC 0082)
- Austin-Bergstrom International Airport event tickets, Austin-Bergstrom International Airport (Tex.)
  Presidents -- United States; Clinton, Bill, 1946-
  - Two tickets to the grand opening celebration of the Austin-Bergstrom International Airport with guest President Bill Clinton, April 21, 1999 (Folder SMC 0083)
- President George W. and First Lady Laura Bush photograph, undated
  Presidents -- United States; Bush, George W. (George Walker), 1946-; Bush, Laura Welch, 1946-
  - Photograph of President and First Lady Bush in front of a menorah. Inscribed to Mara Elizabeth Levy an signed by the Bushes [8" x 10"] color, undated (Folder SMC 0084)
- Rocky Schenck postcard, undated; Schenck, Rocky
  Artists -- Texas; Huddle, William Henry
  - One postcard, not mailed, with a note from Schenck indicating that his grandfather, William Henry Huddle painted the card's artwork "The Surrender of Santa Ana", undated (Folder SMC 0085)
- Arjen van der Sluis collection on Mariana Yampolsky, 2002
  Women photographers -- Mexico; Yampolsky, Mariana, 1925-2002
  - Photocopies of articles on Mariana Yampolsky and a press release, 2002 (Folder SMC 0086)
- El Paso Museum of Art brochures, 2002-2003; El Paso Museum of Art
  Photographers -- Texas; Varela, Willie, 1950-
  - Two brochures for the El Paso Museum of Art's exhibition titled "Crossing Over: Photographs and New Video Installations by Willie Varela", 2002-2003 (Folder SMC 0087)
- Barbara Whitehead broadside, 2003; Whitehead, Barbara Mathews
  Women artists -- Texas
  - Broadside created for Texas Literary Outlaws by Steve Davis. 9" x 12" black and white broadside is signed by Whitehead and numbered 7/10, 2003 (Folder SMC 0088)
- Austin Film Festival promotional material, 2006; Austin Film Festival (Austin, Tex.)
  Film festivals -- Texas -- Austin
  - Passes, invitations, flyers, and tote bag from the Austin Film Festival, 2006 (Folder SMC 0089)
- Hecho en Tejas Day proclamations, 2007
  Mexican Americans -- Texas -- Literary collections; Proclamations -- Texas; Gilb, Dagoberto, 1950-
  - House Resoluntion no. 285, declaring February 10th as Hecho en Tejas Day at the Texas State Capitol. 4 copies. Each has the official state seal, February 8, 2007 (Folder SMC 0090)
- Jovita Mireles interview, 1981
  Education, Bilingual -- Texas; Mireles, Jovita González, 1904-1983
  - Transcript of Margaret Wead's interview with Jovita Mireles, June 17, 1981 (Folder SMC 0091)
- Encino Press pamphlet, undated
  Book design; Encino Press
  - "A Private Press Profile" pamphlet about Encino Press from the MLA Quarterly, undated (Folder SMC 0092)
- Tommy Lee Jones poem, 2006; Jones, Tommy Lee, 1946-
  Actors
  - "Doggerel" typed peom by Tommy Lee Jones, signed and dated, Tesuque, New Mexico, June 2006 (Folder SMC 0093)
- El Progreso promotional materials, circa 2004
  Texas -- Newspapers
  - Promotional materials for El Progreso, 1939-1940: The Work of Rodolfo Zepeda Mirabal and Dora Cervera Mirabal, by Rosie Mirabal Garza. Includes a bookmark, booklet and acknowledgements, circa 2004 (Folder SMC 0094)
- Harriet Doerr correspondence, 1995-1998; Doerr, Harriet; Woolmer, J. Howard
  Women authors; Woolmer, J. Howard
  - Correspondence between author Harriet Doerr and bibliographer, J. Howard Woolmer, 1995-1998 (Folder SMC 0095)
    Authors -- Interviews; McCarthy, Cormac, 1933-; Winfrey, Oprah
- Cormac McCarthy interview on the Oprah Winfrey Show, 2008
  - VHS tape and two DVD copies of Cormac McCarthy's interview on the Oprah Winfrey Show, 2008 (Folder SMC 0096)
- Honeysuckle Rose press kit, circa 1980
  Motion pictures; Nelson, Willie, 1933-
  - Press kit for Honeysuckle Rose. Includes articles about stars Willie Nelson, Dyan Cannon, Slim Pickens and Amy Irving, producer Gene Taft, director Jerry Schatzberg, and executive producer Sydney Pollack., circa 1980 (Folder SMC 0097)
  - Full cast and crew list for Honeysuckle Rose, circa 1980 (Folder SMC 0097)
  - 3 black and white photographs of Honeysuckle Rose, circa 1980 (Folder SMC 0097)
- Stevie Ray Vaughan Double Trouble poster, undated
  Musicians -- Texas; Music -- Posters; Vaughan, Stevie Ray
  - Poster for Stevie Vaughan and Double Trouble. Handwritten at the bottom: "Every Tuesday in April Cheatham Street", undated (Folder SMC 0098)
- Trinity University alumni letters, 1999
  College theater -- Texas; Baker, Paul, 1911-2009
  - Photocopies of letters from Trinity University alumni reflecting on the Ruth Taylor Theater, 1999 (Folder SMC 0099)
- Edwin "Bud" Shrake and Dan Jenkins screenplay, 1985; Shrake, Edwin; Jenkins, Dan
  - Typed copy of screenplay for "Beverly Hills Cop II" by Edwin "Bud" Shrake and Dan Jenkins. First page is dated and says "First Draft", August 25, 1985 (Folder SMC 0100)
- Austin City Limits program, 1994; Austin city limits (Television program)
  Willis, Kelly; Foster, Radney
  - Austin City Limits program from the episode featuring Radney Foster and Kelly Willis. Front cover is signed with a note by Foster, March 9, 1994 (Folder SMC 0101)
- Dick J. Reavis essays, 2008-2010; Reavis, Dick J.
  Journalism -- Texas
  - Copies of Dick Reavis' essays for "The Rag" blog, 2008-2010 (Folder SMC 0102)
- Bill Moyers' Journal transcript, 1979
  Authors -- Interviews; Moyers, Bill D.; Graves, John, 1920-2013
  - Transcript from episode of Bill Moyers' Journal called "John Graves: The Head Varmint of Hard Scrabble." Transcript consists of an interview between Moyers and Graves, July 23, 1979 (Folder SMC 0103)
- Alton and Irene Schwarz photograph, undated
  William D. Wittliff
  - Photograph of curb where Bill Wittliff wrote his name in the cement. He wrote "Billy Wittliff June 3, 1950." Includes a page from the donors explaining the story behind the photograph [8" x 10"] color, undated (Folder SMC 0104)
- Jim Kimmel typescript and photographs, 2004; Kimmel, Jim, 1943-
  San Marcos River (Tex.) -- Description and travel
  - Typescript of draft for Jim Kimmel's book, The San Marcos: A River's Story. Includes 8 color photographs and a letter from Kimmel to Connie Todd of the Wittliff Collections, 2004 (Folder SMC 0105)
- Peggy Walters collection on the founding of J. Frank Dobie High School, 1968-2010
  Dobie, J. Frank (James Frank), 1888-1964
  - Photocopies of letters, card and a program related to the founding and dedication of J. Frank Dobie High School in Houston, Texas, 1968-2010 (Folder SMC 0106)
- J. Frank Dobie photographs, 1918-1956
  - Three photographs of J. Frank Dobie, 1918-1956 (Folder SMC 0107)
- Lucky Attal collection on Francisco "Pancho" Villa, 1916, undated
  Mexican-American border region -- History -- 20th century; Villa, Pancho, 1878-1923
  - Pamphlet, cover title--"Pancho Villa: Terror of Mexico, Descriptive Illustrated History of the Mexican Revolution" by Max Stein, 1916. p. 3 is signed by J. Frank Dobie with a note "as scarce as hen's teeth" (Folder SMC 0108)
  - One photograph of Villa with the negative. Inscription on back indicates the picture was taken in Mexico City, early in his career, undated (Folder SMC 0108)
  - One group photograph with Villa and Pershing identified, undated (Folder SMC 0108)
- Leonard Sanders letter, 1999
  Sanders, Leonard
  - Letter to Blankenship from Leonard Sanders, December 28, 1999 (Folder SMC 0109)
- Brant Bingamon interview with Bud Shrake, 2008
  Authors -- Interviews; Shrake, Edwin
  - Copies of a series of emails in which Bingamon interviews Shrake, 2008 (Folder SMC 0110)
- De Pree Art Center and Gallery brochures, 1997-2003; De Pree Art Center & Gallery
  Photography, Artistic -- Exhibitions
  - Brochures for two exhibitions: Loteria: Artists' Variations of the Traditional Mexican Game (2003) and Steve Nelson: Solo Flight (1997) (Folder SMC 0111)
- Dorothy Sloan auction catalogues, 2003; Dorothy Sloan--Books (Firm)
  Auction catalogs
  - Catalogues for auction 12 "The Daniel G. Volkmann Jr. Collection of The Zamorano 80" and auction 13 "A Few Good Maps and Manuscripts Touching upon the History of Texas, California, the Southwest, Mexico and the Borderlands.", February 2003 (Folder SMC 0112)
- J. Frank Dobie photograph, circa 1959
  Dobie, J. Frank (James Frank), 1888-1964; Dobie, Bertha McKee, 1890-
  - Photograph of J. Frank Dobie and friends. Persons identified are Dobie, Mrs. Bertha Dobie, Mrs. Lillian Bedichek, Sue McBee, Bevlan Smith, Clara Lewis, Jack Whithead (son of Clara Lewis) [8.5" x 12.5"] black/white, circa November 1959 (Folder SMC 0113)
- Katherine Anne Porter photograph, undated
  Women authors, American -- Texas -- 20th century; Katherine Anne Porter, 1890-1980
  - Photograph of Katherine Anne Porter [8" x 10"] black/white, undated (Folder SMC 0114)
- John Graves screenplay, 2006; Graves, John, 1920-2013
  - Screenplay by John Graves based on his short story "The Last Running" with revisions by Connie Todd. From cover: "Revised draft for cast reading at Southwestern Writers Collection", September 6, 2006 (Box Unknown)
- "W. K. ""Kip"" Stratton collection of J. Frank Dobie", 1965-1968
  - Photocopies of documents pertaining the University of Texas' purchase of J. Frank Dobie's ranch and the establishment of the Paisano writing program, 1965-1968 (Folder SMC 0116)
- James Kelman letters, 1980
  Women authors, American -- Texas -- 20th century; Hughes, Mary Gray
  - Photocopies of letters to James Kelman, predominantly from Mary Gray Hughes, 1980 (Folder SMC 0117)
- Mary Margaret Farabee collection of Red-Headed Stranger, 1986-1995
  Advertising -- Motion pictures; Nelson, Willie, 1933-; William D. Wittliff
  - Clippings, three photographs, promotional materials, correspondence related to the movie Red-Headed Stranger, starring Willie Nelson, written and directed by Bill Wittliff. Includes a promotional postcard signed by Nelson, 1986-1995 (Folder SMC 0118)
- Jean Granberry Schnitz presentation, 2009
  Folklore -- Texas; Dobie, J. Frank (James Frank), 1888-1964
  - Copy of presentation titled "J. Frank Dobie's Brush Country Roots" by Jean Granberry Schnitz given to the Texas Folklore Society. Also inclides a typed draft, April 10, 2009 (Folder SMC 0119)
- Texas Folklore Society programs, 1997-2009; Texas Folklore Society
  Folklore -- Texas
  - Programs for the Texas Folklore Society's annual meetings, 1997-2009 (Folder SMC 0120)
- N. Scott Momaday clippings and photocopied photographs, 2011, undated; Momaday, N. Scott, 1934-
  - Two clippings related to author N. Scott Momaday and eight black and white photocopies of photographs by Scott, 2011, undated (Folder SMC 0121)
- Nolan Porterfield collection of Grover Lewis, 1957-1964
  Lewis, Grover
  - Letters from Grover Lewis to Nolan Porterfield and Mr. Edel (Folder SMC 0122)
  - Photocopy of "Wait for Morning Child: a play in one act" by Grover Lewis (Folder SMC 0122)
  - Photocopies of articles articles and poems by Lewis appearing in Renaissance, Notes from the Undergrond and Fort Worth Star Telegram, 1957-1964 (Folder SMC 0122)
  - Photocopies of photographs of Grover Lewis, and two clippings discussing Lewis (Folder SMC 0122)
  - Recordings on CD by Porterfield of Lewis reading poetry and singing, along with a copy of the poem "Tom Joad" by Woodie Guthrie, 1957-1964 (Folder SMC 0122)
  - Typed copies of short stories "A Country Man on a Long Day's Journey", and "A Leaden Finger"; poems "Poem for the Wreckage of Children" and "In Loco Parentis", 1957-1964 (Folder SMC 0122)
- Texas Book Festival promotional material, 2007; Texas Book Festival
  Festivals -- Texas; William D. Wittliff
  - Invitation for the Texas Book Festival including a booklet with schedule and list of authors. Feature's Bill Wittliff's photographs from Lonesome Dove, 2007 (Folder SMC 0123)
- Al Lowman card and poster, 2008; Lowman, Al
  - New Year's card from Al and Darlyne Lowman and a 12" x 9" gray cardstock print with a portrait of Henry Miller by Barbara Holman and the poem "Imagination", 2008 (Folder SMC 0124)
- Ann Rapp remarks on Bud Shrake, May 12, 2009; Rapp, Ann
  Speeches, addresses, etc.; Shrake, Edwin
  - Two typed pages of remarks by Ann Rapp at the graveside service for Bud Shrake, dated and signed by Rapp, May 12, 2009 (Folder SMC 0125)
- J. Frank Dobie university transcript, 2006
  - Two copies of J. Frank Dobie's transcript from Columbia University, where he attended from 1912-1914. Includes letters between SWWC, executor of Dobie's estate Cecilia Rohloff, and the registrar's office at Columbia concerning authorization to release the record, 2006 (Folder SMC 0126)
- Ben Guttery collection of Edwin Lanham, 2006
  Lanham, Edwin, 1904-1979
  - Clippings, correspondence and research materials related to Edwin Lanham, including information about the probate of Lanham's will, 2006 (Folder SMC 0127)
- Steve Cox collection on Deadhead Miles, 1970-2008; Cox, Steve
  - Copy of screenplay for Deadhead Miles by Terrence Malick, 1970 (Folder SMC 0128)
  - "Deadhead Miles and me: a rambling reminiscence" by Steve Cox, October 28, 2008 (Folder SMC 0128)
- Charles Shadle score and recording, 2005
  Composers; Shadle, Charles
  - Score and recording of "Penny Ballad of Elvious Ricks, c. 1927" by Charles Shadle, based on the poetry of R. G. Vliet. Piece is dedicated to Ann Vliet, 2005 (Folder SMC 0129)
- Preston and Dorris Connally collection of Elithe Hamilton Kirkland, 1956-1998
  Women authors, American -- Texas -- 20th century; Kirkland, Elithe Hamilton
  - Clippings, poems, reviews, book catalog (in German), postcards, promotional materials, biographical sketch, 1956-1998 (Folder SMC 0130)
- Richard M. Dalton books on CD, undated
  Dalton, R. Merrill
  - "Padre Island: a novel about the National Park Service and antiquities theft", undated (Folder SMC 0131)
  - "A Photographic Guide to Mexico", undated (Folder SMC 0131)
- Big Bend National Park brochure and slides, undated
  Big Bend National Park (Tex.)
  - Vintage brochure of Big Bend National Park and eight "Armchair Traveler" slides depicting the park, undated (Folder SMC 0132)
- Robert T. Hill article, 1901
  Rio Grande; Hill, Robert Thomas, 1858-1941
  - Article titled "Running the cañons of the Rio Grande" by Robert T. Hill, published in The Century magazine, February 1901 (Folder SMC 0133)
- Susan Toomey Frost drawings, undated; Frost, Susan Toomey, 1941-
  Decorative arts; Frost, Susan Toomey, 1941-
  - Drawings with measurements of the design of a mosiac-topped table, undated (Folder SMC 0134)
- Larry McMurtry reading transcript, 1983; McNeese State University
  Speeches, addresses, etc.; McMurtry, Larry
  - Two copies of transcript of a reading Larry McMurtry gave at McNeese State University's Creative Writing Program Talk #7, October 7, 1983 (Folder SMC 0135)
- J. Frank Dobie promotional material, circa 1960
  - Domino Records mailer promoting the record "J. Frank Dobie tells The Ghost Bull of the Mavericks and other tales", circa 1960 (Folder SMC 0136)
- Kiki Wheelock collection of Jeanne Dixon, 2009-2011
  Dixon, Jeanne